So friends, today we are going to talk about
ICC Lombard,
what exactly does ICC Lombard company do
and how has its business been, so ICC
Lombard is the Sikkim Largest General
Insurance in India, so here
I will tell you about the first largest general insurance in the end,
you have to watch this video till the end of the video,
then you will know who is the first market
leader of this segment or of this business,
so ICC Lombard friends
comes in the second position with a market share
of 8.71%, in November 22 this market
share of this company was 8.7%, the company caters to the
largest general insurance, you
can see here the largest general
insurance is New Indian Insurance, so
friends, the first one is New
India Assurance, I was going to tell you in the last,
but I have already told you, right now the
market share is
13.63%, so yes, the one who has bought ICC Lombard
and those who are thinking that
they are the market leaders, in particular, in the
health insurance
market or which  There is also an insurance
market, it is not like this friends,
New India Insurance is the
market leader here, there Major General Insurance is
Nav Aa in India, Bajaj Allianz
General Insurance, SBI General
Insurance and HDFC Co, so these are basically
three companies, I had HDFC EGO's
Live Finch Insurance earlier, it is not there now,
I have ICC Lombard's peer
analysis, let us see a little,
friends, here are all these competitors,
you can give information about ICC Lombard's competitors here, New Indian
Insurance is Bajaj Allianz, BI HDFC,
we have discussed that, there is Max Bhupa
General Insurance, Reliance General Insurance,
Royal Sundaram General
Insurance
and United India Insurance, this
company is complete with ICC Lombards,
where is motor insurance included,
they are giving competition right now, so there is motor
insurance, health insurance, travel insurance,
home insurance, so
apart from all the insurance that comes in it,
in life insurance, that is ICICI and HDFC
Life, that is okay, that is a different market,
this is a different market, first you have to understand that
insurance  The market doesn't just mean life
insurance and links. Many
people only know that insurance means links.
Now, their brand recognition is established,
which is a good thing. However, the
company itself hasn't seen much growth.
We'll discuss that in another video.
But first, let's talk about what
insurances exist other than life insurance. When you buy bike
insurance, car insurance,
health insurance,
travel insurance, or
home insurance, that
too becomes spring-loaded. Let's
discuss a little about the company's business.
Friends, ICC Lombard is a tremendous joint
venture between Bank D, ICC Bank, and The
FairX Financial Holdings Limited.
Many people didn't know that this was a joint
venture. It's basically a company, but together,
they're still running.
Friends,
you can see this Canadian company here. The
company was founded in 2000 in Mumbai, India. ICC
Lombard offers a wide range of general insurance
products. Then we discussed
motor insurance.  If we talk about travel insurance,
health insurance and home insurance
financials,
then ICC Lombard's financial performance is
strong in this India. If we
talk about Ref 22, then they generated net profit of Rs
127 crore, Rs
12 to 71 crore, here their net
profit is relief
in 2022,
that is, this was the net profit from March 2021 to March 2022,
and the company's gross direct
premium and return, which is
called GDP, means basically
how much net premium they have received in a year, it
is big by 10.4% and
here you can see that it is Rs 24000
638 crore, basically this
can be called their net revenue,
if we look at the real time statistics here, friends, then
today of July ICC Lombard share price is
around Rs 1300, the
rest of the company market capitalization
in Rs 50000 crore, milk plastic's n step is included
in this, mid's apply's last
cap is included in this  Its P ratio
is 37. So, in terms of its P ratio, we are going to
discuss whether there is exactly over
volume or there is value inside. We
can also discuss a little bit whether we
can invest here or not.
ICC Lambadi is the leading in general
insurance India. We have
seen this confusion. The rest of the important thing is that the
general insurance market is going to
grow at a rate of 12%. That
means there is a good growth. This is
going to bring growth in general insurance here.
Obviously, I myself do general
insurance. I have car
insurance, bike insurance,
health insurance. So,
obviously, I think this market will do well
in the coming 10 years.
Now, we were looking at a little bit of growth here. Here, the
market cap is
showing a little bit higher. The remaining
dividend is 0.75%. You will
not get a decent dividend. I
like one very good thing about insurance companies that they get money
very quickly. I mean, if you are
talking about banks.  You will do it, okay, take any bank,
HDFC Bank, they have to pay the money first,
then they
get interest from there and then, but this does
not happen with an insurance company, the
insurance company already gets the premium, the
money is already paid, later
if they have to make a claim, they make the claim, it is a
simple thing, it is not that difficult, just like now,
if you suppose my tax is
excellent, then I will go and make a claim,
now the probability of my tax having an accident is
very low, so I will pay the
premium, I will remain in India,
but in 10 years, if my tax has an accident once or twice, then only the
company will have to pay my
premium,
whatever I claim, it is a very good and
strong business model, I think Warren Buffer
also invested very well in the life insurance or health or
general insurance company,
friends, I
remember this so much, I still feel that I
invested or was invested earlier because
seeing this, he himself said and
also made a court decision.
I really liked the insurance companies because
they already have money. Rest of the
friends, if we talk about learning ratios, it is
around 37-38. We have seen N Founded, we have
also seen the air, we have also seen the employers.
Now take a look at
their statements,
their results have been quite strong. You can see that in a
way there is some remaining growth. There
is consolidation here in the revenue graph.
Here you can see friends, the total
revenue has grown by 12.95%
in quarter 22. In December 2022, you can see that it was
14%. So there is a little normal valley here.
If we talk about the statistics, the
performance has been, their quarterly performance, their
price to earning ratio is
decreasing. Now what exactly is price to earning ratio, it
means P
ratio. Okay, now it is PERI ratio.
Friends, the valuation of the company, so the
valuation of the company was the lowest in quarter 22.  Yes,
you can see that in Q2, the revenue has been
quite low compared to Q2 2013.
Now is a very good opportunity to invest, that is
why we are discussing this on this channel. If
you look at the annual, friends,
see how low the price running ratio is
here, isn't it? If compared with every other company, then the
lowest here is
in 2022. Price to Clashes Flow Ratio
is also a camera here, that is also worth seeing.
Yes, if we look at their annual performance here, friends,
you can see that their total
revenue growth is continuously big.
I liked this the most because
obviously people will pay premiums, people
will pay very high premiums and their
claim process reduces a lot.
If you see, the operating profit is in blue color, then
you will see in orange color here, you
can see that the operating profit
of the company is also continuously big. Here you can see
friends, total revenue group and operating
income, this will also be visible to you.  Friends, there was a growth of 30% in
operating income, this is a very good
thing, but here you can see that
in 2021 there has been an operating growth of 13%,
6.34
14.332, this is tremendous growth, if you look at the
total revenue growth of operating growth here,
32% 3%, then there will be continuous revenue
growth or operating profit margins have
also been very good, the cross
profit margin of the company is also very good,
continuous income is big, continuous income will
also increase and by the way,
if the company declares dividend, I
liked it very much,
I like their management because they
think a little about the share holders, so many people
are invested, obviously some dividend is distributed, and
if I talk about earnings, then
friends, here
you can see a little concentration on a quarterly basis, annual continuously, the
earnings of the company are big,
you can see this, the
trading they have focused here,
that too  If the company is going to make continuous earnings, then
obviously the share price will
also increase. Let
us talk a little about the technical aspects. Friends,
what is the current chart of ICC Lombard?
Many people are confused about what to do
exactly. It
got very good support. Friends,
below is its monthly chart, its cycle indicator
is RS. RSS is about to cross 60 now,
so the bullishness in the company means the bullishness in the stock. There is
strength in the stock. Here you can see friends,
its support level is around 1200. Or it has respected the
support level of 1200 very well.
Now the resistance level
is around 1700. From there the
stock can move. If you want to invest now, you can
invest. You can send ₹150. You get a
record. There are
definitely chances of the stock going up. I hope
friends, you found this video informative. This
video must have added some value.
If you liked this video, like the video and
subscribe to the channel. See you again
friends.  Till then Jai Hind in the next video